Welcome to the Video Caption Generator tutorial.
This application helps you create professional subtitles quickly and easily.
You can upload video files or record live speech for real-time transcription.
The speech recognition technology supports over 50 languages worldwide.
Simply click the upload button to select your video file from your computer.
Supported formats include MP4, WebM, MOV, and AVI files.
For live recording, click the microphone button and speak clearly.
The application will automatically convert your speech to text in real-time.
You can edit the generated subtitles using the timeline editor below.
Drag the subtitle blocks to adjust timing or click to edit the text content.
Translation features allow you to convert subtitles to different languages.
Configure your Google Translate API key in settings for translation support.
Customize the appearance with font size, color, and background options.
Export your subtitles in multiple formats including SRT, WebVTT, and ASS.
You can also export videos with burned-in subtitles for final distribution.
The application works offline for basic features and includes dark mode support.
Keyboard shortcuts help speed up your workflow during editing sessions.
Press Space to play or pause, and use arrow keys to navigate the timeline.
The responsive design ensures the application works on both desktop and mobile devices.
Thank you for using the Video Caption Generator. Happy subtitling!